<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1" xmlns:ttp="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#parameter" ttp:timeBase="media" xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#style" xml:lang="en" xmlns:ttm="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1#metadata"> 
	<head> 
		<metadata> 
			<ttm:title> 
				Twitter Subtitles
			</ttm:title> 
		</metadata> 
		<styling> 
			<style id="s0" tts:backgroundColor="black" tts:fontStyle="normal" tts:fontSize="16" tts:fontFamily="sansSerif" tts:color="white" /> 
		</styling> 
	</head> 
	<body tts:textAlign="center" style="s0"> 
		<div> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:00:01" id="p89" end="00:00:21">Subtitle content provided by Twitter</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:00:21" id="p90" end="00:00:45">brunella: At #JISC10 tweeting as @goinedge - good exhibitors reminded me how much I&apos;ve learnt being an e-learning activist! http://j.mp/c4sn2X [08:52GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:00:45" id="p91" end="00:01:21">andypowe11: &quot;i am one screwed up vice-chancellor&quot; - martin bean talking at #jisc10 [08:52GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:21" id="p92" end="00:01:35">damyantipatel: &quot;i am one screwed up vice-chancellor&quot; - martin bean talking at #jisc10 (via @andypowe11) [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:35" id="p93" end="00:01:41">FleurP: Martin Bean starting his keynote #jisc10 [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:41" id="p94" end="00:01:44">timmarshall: Martin Bean may be a maverick, that&apos;s why he&apos;s one of the most visonary guys in British HE    #jisc10 [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:44" id="p95" end="00:01:50">andypowe11: &quot;i am an australian and therefore you cannot offend me ... but i can offend you&quot; - martin bean talking at #jisc10 [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:50" id="p96" end="00:01:50">paulwalk: Enjoying Martin Bean&apos;s intro #jisc10 [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:50" id="p97" end="00:01:53">lukask: Listening/watching #jisc10 livestream, with an Australian accent ;-) http://www.jisc.ac.uk/jisc10 [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:53" id="p98" end="00:01:55">alastairdunning: Australians cannot be offended - martin bean at the #jisc10 conference [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:55" id="p99" end="00:01:55">lucyrstone: Well I&apos;ve woken up now listening to Mr Bean at #jisc10 [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:55" id="p100" end="00:01:58">manmalik: #jisc10 Martin Bean  should stop doing the same intro he gives everywhere :) [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:01:58" id="p101" end="00:02:21">richardmobbs: Watch Martin Bean OU VC at #JISC10 [08:53GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:02:21" id="p102" end="00:02:21">simonhodson99: Can&apos;t get on the wifi! Boo! #jisc10 Slow tweets from phone... [08:54GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:02:21" id="p103" end="00:02:49">llordllama: OU VC Martin Bean now speaking #jisc10 [08:54GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:02:49" id="p104" end="00:02:56">PatParslow: #jisc10 oh I *like* Martin Bean CV of the OU :-) can he be our VC please? [08:54GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:02:56" id="p105" end="00:03:01">andypowe11: globalisation - there are roughly 200 million students who study outside their home country - distance education is &quot;on fire&quot; - #jisc10 [08:54GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:03:01" id="p106" end="00:03:09">alphabeta85: #jisc10 distance education is on fire... Like that phrase :-) [08:55GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:03:09" id="p107" end="00:03:09">karenblakeman: Wondering if I &apos;m going to get any work done today - following #uksg and #jisc10 [08:55GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:03:09" id="p108" end="00:03:18">beckacurrant: massification is challenging all of us to look at application of technology to meet demand #jisc10 [08:55GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:03:18" id="p109" end="00:03:31">FleurP: @janetfinlay me neither think it hates ipod tech #jisc10 wifi [08:55GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:03:31" id="p110" end="00:03:35">lady_jane: Click and mortar growing faster than brick and mortar #JISC10 [08:55GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:03:35" id="p111" end="00:03:52">andypowe11: massification - we cannot build physical infrastructure fast enough to cope with demand in higher education #jisc10 [08:55GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:03:52" id="p112" end="00:03:55">romieh: Globalisation, massification and privatisation M Bean at #jisc10 [08:55GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:03:55" id="p113" end="00:04:09">walkyouhome: Listening to #jisc10 whilst populating spreadsheets. Multitasking! [08:55GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:09" id="p114" end="00:04:15">llordllama: Distance learning is growth area, as cannot build enough brick and morter HEIs.  But 1/3 HE students are in private institutions #jisc10 [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:15" id="p115" end="00:04:23">goinedge: #JISC10 Martin Bean - Open University -  &quot;I&apos;m Australian so you cannot offend me&quot; :) Keynote about changing nature of HE [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:23" id="p116" end="00:04:36">diarmaid: Martin Bean opens the JISC Conference 2010 - watch live here http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:36" id="p117" end="00:04:38">sheilmcn: 1 in 3 studnets globally are in private HE provision #jisc10 [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:38" id="p118" end="00:04:43">beckacurrant: private sector will play evr increasing role in how HE is provided we all need 2 figure out how ths will work ovr the coming years #jisc10 [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:43" id="p119" end="00:04:46">SueFolley: Mega=trends in HE: Globalisation, Massification and Privatisation - Martin Bean #jisc10 [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:46" id="p120" end="00:04:52">suukii: Martin Bean: globalisation, massification, privitisation. Changing nature of HE.  #JISC10 [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:52" id="p121" end="00:04:52">lucyrstone: To implement change more mavericks are needed? Martin Bean self proclaimed maverick #jisc10 [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:04:52" id="p122" end="00:05:07">dajbconf: #jisc10 Globalization, Massification &amp; Privatization = &apos;megatrends&apos; in HE. [08:56GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:07" id="p123" end="00:05:10">chriskeene: OU VC says more private sector involvement is a trend coming to the UK. sssssssh don&apos;t tell sussex students! #jisc10 [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:10" id="p124" end="00:05:14">beckacurrant: need to educate citizens for new types of work #jisc10 won&apos;t you leave some people behind as they don&apos;t have access to tech? [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:14" id="p125" end="00:05:19">ruthycl: Private sector to play an increasing role in HE. Martin Bean VC OU  #jisc10 [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:19" id="p126" end="00:05:20">manmalik: #jisc10 privitisation of Universities may be on the cards in the next 10 years [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:20" id="p127" end="00:05:27">m_hopwood: &quot;Globalisation, massification, privatisation are key trends in HE&quot; - M. Bean at #jisc10 - ok, but why r they happening? #reality #education [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:27" id="p128" end="00:05:35">briankelly: The Uk is only just waking up to the increasing role of ptivitisation on HE says Martin Bean at #jisc10, no doubt upsetting lefties here [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:35" id="p129" end="00:05:41">diarmaid: What are the challenges in higher education? Watch Martin Bean vice chancellor of the open university here http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:41" id="p130" end="00:05:44">llordllama: Need to educate our citizens for new kinds of work #jisc10 [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:44" id="p131" end="00:05:56">dajbconf: #jisc10 &apos;Sunset&apos; and &apos;sunrise&apos; new technology. Jargon at it&apos;s finest. ;-) [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:56" id="p132" end="00:05:58">alisonpope: Martin Bean OU VC, Australian, Maverick, Anarchist, cannot be offended  #jisc10 [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:05:58" id="p133" end="00:06:06">beckacurrant: digitl divide more about those that ustand how to use and apply tech as a necessity rather than just getting access to tech #jisc10 [08:57GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:06" id="p134" end="00:06:06">lj_arts: #jisc10 we need to educate for new types of work... am thinking about what this means for arts education. [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:06" id="p135" end="00:06:06">fooflington: You&apos;re in a maze of twisty passages all alike. There is a hash-tag. You can go N S E W UP DOWN #jisc10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:06" id="p136" end="00:06:10">damyantipatel: &apos;1 on 3 HE student is in a private inst&apos; #jisc10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:10" id="p137" end="00:06:12">iltman: Finding that watching from my desk doesn&apos;t mean I can multitask #jisc10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:12" id="p138" end="00:06:13">DrNickPearce: BEAN digital divide as about being understanding of tech rather than access, i&apos;d agree with that #jisc10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:13" id="p139" end="00:06:14">sheilmcn: Digital divide is about knowledge not access #jisc10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:14" id="p140" end="00:06:14">Marjakingma: Trying to follow #JISC10 and work at the same time. Bit of a challenge. 
Martin Bean on HE and role to bridge digital divide. [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:14" id="p141" end="00:06:29">manmalik: #jisc10 technology should have its sunrise and sunset and we need to move on... [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:29" id="p142" end="00:06:32">MarkPower: Would like to see Martin Bean&apos;s keynote on Digital Divide as he just described it in similar terms to how it was put at #pelc10 (#jisc10) [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:32" id="p143" end="00:06:36">manmalik: #jisc10 STEM and innovation economy linked :) [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:36" id="p144" end="00:06:37">herrdoktorc: STEM is key for a competitive workforce #science #jisc10 #scivote [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:37" id="p145" end="00:06:38">marianneshepp: Megatrends in HE: globalisation, massification, privatisation. Martin Bean at  #jisc10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:38" id="p146" end="00:06:38">andypowe11: challenges - need to education students for new types of work - STEM is key for a competitive workforce - innovation is the key #jisc10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:38" id="p147" end="00:06:45">beckacurrant: STEM key for a competitive workforce innovation economy fueled by STEM need to be creative in ways to grow and nurture this #jisc10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:06:45" id="p148" end="00:07:05">diarmaid: @openuniversity Watch Martin Bean - live webcast from the JISC 2010 Conference http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [08:58GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:07:05" id="p149" end="00:07:07">timmarshall: #jisc10   digitial literacy is about application of technology to personal lives [08:59GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:07:07" id="p150" end="00:07:08">PatParslow: #jisc10 STEM undeniably essential. Someone tell my VC pls? [08:59GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:07:08" id="p151" end="00:07:13">dajbconf: #jisc10 I&apos;m assuming STEM = Science, Technology, Engineering, Maths, yes? [08:59GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:07:13" id="p152" end="00:07:18">alphabeta85: Innovation is the key, STEM is critical - Martin Bean #jisc10 [08:59GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:07:18" id="p153" end="00:07:27">mylesdanson: Tim OShea mentions LFHE summit JISC involvement. See Portfolio for Senior Managers &amp; nice graphic: http://bit.ly/d52yuy #jisc10 [08:59GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:07:27" id="p154" end="00:07:50">MarkPower: @sheilmcn Well....it&apos;s both. But at least the knowledge/motivation/skills side is now being highlighted #jisc10 [08:59GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:07:50" id="p155" end="00:08:03">Emma_M_TECHDIS: Digital divide now more about understanding tech than having access to it - interesting thought #jisc10 [08:59GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:03" id="p156" end="00:08:06">carenmilloy: #JISC10 OU VC Bean - digital divide isn&apos;t about access but about people understanding how to make real use and sense of digital content [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:06" id="p157" end="00:08:29">kirkstuff: Forgive my ignorance, what is STEM? #JISC10 [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:29" id="p158" end="00:08:29">beckacurrant: need to spend as much time thinking about sense making of info as we do about retrieval of info digital literacy &amp; trusted content #jisc10 [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:29" id="p159" end="00:08:35">chriskeene: Everyone should be watching http://www.jisc.ac.uk/jisc10 now #jisc10 [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:35" id="p160" end="00:08:45">mariekeguy: #jisc10 martin bean, vc open uni, talking about need to teach students to make sense of info [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:45" id="p161" end="00:08:45">FleurP: Need to Transform information into meaningful knowledge &lt;too true #jiscenable #jisc10 [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:45" id="p162" end="00:08:45">beckacurrant: STEM = Science Technology Engineering and Maths for those asking! #jisc10 [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:45" id="p163" end="00:08:54">manmalik: #jisc10 trusted content - meaning changing [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:54" id="p164" end="00:08:57">dajbconf: Prediction: trusted content - what it is and where to go for it. #jisc10 [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:57" id="p165" end="00:08:58">MarkPower: Need to look at sense making of information, not just retrieval of information. Trust of content will be a big issue #jisc10 [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:08:58" id="p166" end="00:09:06">walkyouhome: Libs need to support making sense of information, not just info retrieval #jisc10 [09:00GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:09:06" id="p167" end="00:09:10">damyantipatel: &apos;trust of content&apos; key trend says Martin Bean #jisc10 [09:01GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:09:10" id="p168" end="00:09:17">fooflington: #jisc10 wifi was a little b0rken there... :) [09:01GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:09:17" id="p169" end="00:09:21">cyberdoyle: #jisc10 - &apos;the day google became a verb, a new way of learning, sense making of information, finding trusted content&apos;. Martin Bean. [09:01GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:09:21" id="p170" end="00:09:24">diarmaid: Future Prediction: Biggest trend  is &apos;trust of content&apos; - Martin Bean, Open University - live here http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [09:01GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:09:24" id="p171" end="00:09:33">carenmilloy: Biggest trend to rise up will be about trusted content - this is critical to library role #JISC10 [09:01GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:09:33" id="p172" end="00:09:58">UCL_POD: #jisc10 making sense of information as a skill is now critical [09:01GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:09:58" id="p173" end="00:10:11">kirkstuff: Can&apos;t argue with Martin Beans assertion that libraries are key to making sense of information  ad *trusted information* #JISC10 [09:01GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:11" id="p174" end="00:10:16">briankelly: &quot;There&apos;ll be a trend towards trusted content&quot; says Martin Bean at #jisc10. Hmm - but can trust be applied to DBpedia. [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:16" id="p175" end="00:10:23">EastLondonLives: Big future trend? Martin Bean says it is sensemaking of digital content and establishing measures of trust in it #jisc10 [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:23" id="p176" end="00:10:31">dajbconf: Artificial barriers between secondary, FE &amp; HE will &apos;kill us&apos; #jisc10 &lt;--Amen! [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:31" id="p177" end="00:10:35">DrNickPearce: BEAN STEM subjects key, i agree Sociology, Technology, Education and Media studies #jisc10 [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:35" id="p178" end="00:10:36">FleurP: Good to see us leaving our guns at the door and work as a sector #jisc10 [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:36" id="p179" end="00:10:41">andypowe11: need to break down current barriers between secondary, further and higher education - need to embed learning for life - #jisc10 [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:41" id="p180" end="00:10:55">cosmo07: M Bean &quot;trusted content&quot; ?? surely  it should be about developing critical skills rather than &apos;certification&apos;  #jisc10 [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:55" id="p181" end="00:10:59">theresabt: Martin bean telling us learning in the workplace needs to become integral #JISC10 [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:10:59" id="p182" end="00:11:05">cardcc: Bean has checked his guns at the door of #jisc10. Not that it shows! [09:02GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:05" id="p183" end="00:11:09">diarmaid: @peskypeople Live BSL signing today at the JISC 2010 conference:  Watch online here &gt; http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:09" id="p184" end="00:11:11">pcheeseman: Libraries need to focus on sense making of information as much as providing access to it, Martin Bean at #jisc10 [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:11" id="p185" end="00:11:14">janetfinlay: Artificial boundaries between different levels of education will kill us - Martin Bean keynote #jisc10 [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:14" id="p186" end="00:11:15">alastairdunning: Failing to break down barriers between secondary, further and higher education will kill the sector #jisc10 [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:15" id="p187" end="00:11:23">lj_arts: #jisc10 we&apos;re perpetuating barriers between stages of lifelong learning and this is what will kill us off - Martin Bean [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:23" id="p188" end="00:11:28">kirkstuff: Although would argue that Wikipedia is widely trusted in library &amp; info circles #JISC10 [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:28" id="p189" end="00:11:33">carenmilloy: #JISC10 martin bean: we have a duty of care and we must remove the barriers between he, fe that we have created- need to be flexible [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:33" id="p190" end="00:11:38">wmjohn: Watching Martin Bean: globalisation, massification, privitisation. Changing nature of HE. #JISC10 WOW! ......... breadth of thought [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:38" id="p191" end="00:11:58">mrnick: Martin Bean opens the JISC Conference 2010 - watch live here http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 (via @diarmaid) [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:11:58" id="p192" end="00:12:14">goinedge: #JISC10 Martin Bean OU : libraries have to support sensemaking not only retrieval of information, learning to be embedded in workplaces [09:03GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:12:14" id="p193" end="00:12:32">paulbrichardson: But perhaps there has been too much emphasis on &apos;trusted content&apos;? That way you can end up with a proliferation of  portals.  #jisc10 [09:04GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:12:32" id="p194" end="00:12:33">mrnick: WiFi seems under strain at #jisc10 or is it just me? [09:04GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:12:33" id="p195" end="00:12:40">beckacurrant: quality of student exp is paramount R UNIS LISTENING?! &amp; wht r we going 2 do abt it rather than just suck R cheeks &amp; say O yes! #jisc10 [09:04GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:12:40" id="p196" end="00:13:12">llordllama: @m_hopwood Well, they don&apos;t make much money. If I was in Humanities I&apos;d be watching out for that funding axe #jisc10 [09:04GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:12" id="p197" end="00:13:13">beckacurrant: I applaud the focus on student experience but want to move on from talking about to DOING something about it &amp; making real changes #jisc10 [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:13" id="p198" end="00:13:17">_peak: Only 28% of students feel their education is relevant, research apparently says (listening to Martin Bean @ #jisc10) [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:17" id="p199" end="00:13:21">owenpeteroberts: Joined up education services, good call for sure (In a cool accent too) #jisc10 [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:21" id="p200" end="00:13:23">hectorpeebles: Excellent streaming quality and content from @Diarmaid &amp; @SwitchNewMedia at The JISC Conference 2010: www.jisc.ac.uk/jisc10 #JISC10 [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:23" id="p201" end="00:13:34">marianneshepp: Need for more flexible learning systems and processes. Existing artificial barriers (secondary, fe, he)&apos;will kill us!&apos; 
Martin Bean  #jisc10 [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:34" id="p202" end="00:13:38">dajbconf: #jisc10 Funny joke, not by 12 year old though - heard it before. ;-) [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:38" id="p203" end="00:13:44">manmalik: #jisc10 never known a worl without fb.mp3,sms, email etc - students of this day and age [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:44" id="p204" end="00:13:45">diarmaid: School is like being on an airplane, you sit down and Turn off all your electronic devices - Martin Bean live http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:13:45" id="p205" end="00:14:04">kubke: Education is like traveling by plane: sit down, be quiet and turn off all electronic devices #JISC10 [09:05GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:14:04" id="p206" end="00:14:25">llordllama: Talking about values of younger students today - but I need constant stimulation too #jisc10 [09:06GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:14:25" id="p207" end="00:14:49">beckacurrant: constant stimulation most challenging value posed by today&apos;s students how can we do this in a large lecture with powerpoint? #jisc10 [09:06GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:14:49" id="p208" end="00:15:05">johnpopham: Martin Bean at #JISC10: A 12 year-old told him going to school is like being on an aeroplane. You have to sit (cont) http://tl.gd/rk4j7 [09:06GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:15:05" id="p209" end="00:15:19">llordllama: Modern students don&apos;t like complexity?  So dumbing down of degrees all round then #jisc10 [09:07GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:15:19" id="p210" end="00:15:28">twichardlee: Martin Bean, Vice Chancellor, OU: Libraries now need to help make sense of volume of information, not just information retrieval. #jisc10 [09:07GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:15:28" id="p211" end="00:15:28">beckacurrant: how well does your uni map with the world we live in and the needs our students have? #jisc10 how do you run your exams???!!! [09:07GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:15:28" id="p212" end="00:15:48">paulbrichardson: Full marks to the bloke just seen stroking his chin at #jisc10. Looked very thoughtful... [09:07GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:15:48" id="p213" end="00:15:53">suukii: Studen values list includes autonomy and constant stimulation maybe some tensions? Martin Bean  #JISC10 follow keynote on stream [09:07GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:15:53" id="p214" end="00:16:06">manmalik: #jisc10 exams criticized by Martin Bean [09:07GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:16:06" id="p215" end="00:16:14">dajbconf: #jisc10 Martin Bean makes great point about antiquated assessment systems in education. [09:08GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:16:14" id="p216" end="00:16:15">mungeo: @briankelly No reason why we can&apos;t communicate trust via metadata, it&apos;s best way :-) #jisc10 [09:08GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:16:15" id="p217" end="00:16:20">m_hopwood: Wondering how many people at #jisc10 could actually build a computer from &quot;scratch&quot;? ;) [09:08GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:16:20" id="p218" end="00:16:35">pat3460: mismatch in assessment but also in teaching and learning. Martin Bean #jisc10 [09:08GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:16:35" id="p219" end="00:16:37">lucyrstone: Digital natives a term made up by people like us - I asked my project students what they thought it meant and they had no idea #jisc10 [09:08GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:16:37" id="p220" end="00:16:47">lukask: Martin Bean: Students hate complexity, bad design, cost, things that get in the way of expression #jisc10 [09:08GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:16:47" id="p221" end="00:16:53">chriskeene: screen grab of that slide #jisc10  http://twitpic.com/1f9yeg [09:08GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:16:53" id="p222" end="00:17:00">manmalik: #jisc10 accreditation bodies need to realise this i.e. exams are not the only way to assess preparedness of students for the working world [09:08GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:17:00" id="p223" end="00:17:12">DrNickPearce: must stop picking my nose when on close up on the livestream #jisc10 [09:09GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:17:12" id="p224" end="00:17:22">damyantipatel: &apos;Understanding students they hate complexity, bad design, things that get in the way&apos; - probably don&apos;t like our OPACs,eresources etc #jisc10 [09:09GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:17:22" id="p225" end="00:17:41">timmarshall: today&apos;s students aspire to individuality, creativity and sharing – not something that is characterised in our exams  #jisc10 [09:09GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:17:41" id="p226" end="00:17:41">jeremyspeller: Just spotted @briankelly stroking his beard - also a worry. #jisc10 [09:09GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:17:41" id="p227" end="00:17:41">llordllama: Does pandering to modern student needs mean when they move into work force they won&apos;t b able to relate 2 any one except their peers? #jisc10 [09:09GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:17:41" id="p228" end="00:18:06">alastairdunning: Universities teaching and learning way out of step with students engagement with the digital world #jisc10 [09:09GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:18:06" id="p229" end="00:18:11">dianebrewster: #jisc10 m bean asking us to think about our institutions - split personality moment - opted for the OU - Sussex too depressing! [09:10GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:18:11" id="p230" end="00:18:15">manmalik: #jisc10 HE is about chatting and interacting and testing and applying ....MB Technology can let you do that [09:10GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:18:15" id="p231" end="00:18:15">llordllama: @chriskeene Modern students sound like sheep &quot;things that friends like&quot; #jisc10 [09:10GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:18:15" id="p232" end="00:18:29">beckacurrant: need 2 have active discourse with students and disclipline rather than focus on tradition and the way things have always been done #jisc10 [09:10GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:18:29" id="p233" end="00:18:38">francesbell: @paulbrichardson ask them what happened to funding for Intute - a very trusted portal whose funding JISC is withdrawing aug 2010 #jisc10 [09:10GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:18:38" id="p234" end="00:18:49">dajbconf: #jisc10 &apos;Clicking and polling improves retention rates&apos;. Really? Long-term? (Hawthorne effect?) [09:10GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:18:49" id="p235" end="00:18:50">manmalik: #jisc10 &quot;My life&quot; = &quot;is digital&quot; [09:10GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:18:50" id="p236" end="00:19:06">wmjohn: Only 28% of students feel their education is relevant, ........... Martin Bean #JISC10   Hmmmm [09:10GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:19:06" id="p237" end="00:19:08">manmalik: #jisc10 &quot;My life&quot; = &quot;is digital&quot; students of today [09:11GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:19:08" id="p238" end="00:19:12">lisaharris: @suukii is that what you did, V early start?! Are you here at #JISC10? [09:11GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:19:12" id="p239" end="00:19:13">Marjakingma: #JISC10 Need to find balance between digital work style and digital life style?  Already outdated! It&apos;s all about life! [09:11GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:19:13" id="p240" end="00:19:18">romieh: Lots of refs to use of PRS yesterday at #jisc10 [09:11GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:19:18" id="p241" end="00:19:22">MarkPower: Absolutely! &quot;Digital Lifestyle?&quot;...&quot;Digital Workstyle?&quot;...It&apos;s just MY LIFE. I subscribe to that view #jisc10 [09:11GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:19:22" id="p242" end="00:19:50">suukii: I think Digital literacy perspectives might answer Bean&apos;s perspective. We need 2be smart too... Academic workloads r a factor too  #JISC10 [09:11GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:19:50" id="p243" end="00:19:54">ostephens: What role the type of lecture Martin Bean is giving in the world he is describing? #jisc10 [09:11GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:19:54" id="p244" end="00:20:04">carenmilloy: Make active discourse central to learning and make use of technology to move all the info online. Make best use of face to face time #jisc10 [09:11GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:20:04" id="p245" end="00:20:08">dajbconf: @angelarees @lucyrstone Even Prensky doesn&apos;t use the terms digital native &amp; digital immigrant any more (2009 paper) #jisc10 [09:12GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:20:08" id="p246" end="00:20:09">cosmo07: finding the balance #jisc10 .. student values are pretty much the same today, just in a different context -digital- [09:12GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:20:09" id="p247" end="00:20:17">briankelly: &quot;Education is multi-channel&quot; Matron Bean at #jisc10 [09:12GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:20:17" id="p248" end="00:20:38">manmalik: #jisc10 informal learning growing ...through technology? [09:12GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:20:38" id="p249" end="00:20:41">kirkstuff: &quot;odd hairy Professors&quot;! #JISC10 [09:12GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:20:41" id="p250" end="00:21:17">llordllama: Talking about multichannel delivery of educational content (assume we&apos;re not talking about Worlds Most Extreme Academics on Drugs #jisc10 [09:12GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:17" id="p251" end="00:21:17">manmalik: #jisc10 quantum mechanics in plain english? TheBBC prog Bang goes the theory [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:17" id="p252" end="00:21:24">HelenBeetham: I&apos;m a bit worried where there is evidence that students want more ICT in their learning #jisc10 [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:24" id="p253" end="00:21:28">llordllama: Bah, OU videos more popular than #randyweasel #jisc10 [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:28" id="p254" end="00:21:31">chriskeene: currently: watching #jisc10 (70%). watching #uksg tweets (20%). Working (10%) [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:31" id="p255" end="00:21:43">suukii: I think However they learn students will expect to be marked, evaluated credited and accredited.   #JISC10 [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:43" id="p256" end="00:21:50">MarkPower: @lucyrstone Have a look at @daveowhite&apos;s blog article on this...natives/immigrants? residents/visitors http://is.gd/bqH8X #jisc10 [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:50" id="p257" end="00:21:51">daveyp: @briankelly &quot;Matron Bean&quot;? Is that a Freudian Typo? ;-) #jisc10 [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:51" id="p258" end="00:21:57">iltman: Ouch #jisc10 [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:21:57" id="p259" end="00:22:19">janehsmith: finally got onto wireless #jisc10 [09:13GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:19" id="p260" end="00:22:19">cosmo07: my 10 yr old son can do better tricks with video montage than #jisc10 [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:19" id="p261" end="00:22:19">llordllama: Okay Mr Upside down man - what did that teach us?  #jisc10 [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:19" id="p262" end="00:22:23">manmalik: #jisc10 very nice video Martin Bean [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:23" id="p263" end="00:22:28">ruthycl: OU &apos;captivating people&apos;s imagination&apos; to educate.  #jisc10 [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:28" id="p264" end="00:22:31">simonhodson99: On!  But very slow... #jisc10 [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:31" id="p265" end="00:22:42">fooflington: Careful not to sensationalise and therefore dumb-down the science/research involved for the mass-market. #jisc10 [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:42" id="p266" end="00:22:43">HelenBeetham: Some great stuff about sharing science experiences on itunes-u etc #jisc10 [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:43" id="p267" end="00:22:44">chriskeene: &apos;megaphones of learning&apos; new buzzword to me  #jisc10 [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:44" id="p268" end="00:22:51">MarkPower: @lucyrstone and @josiefraser&apos;s piece http://is.gd/bqHeB #jisc10 [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:51" id="p269" end="00:22:56">mrnick: Watching #jisc10 stream - audience look gloomy, but in every other shot there&apos;s 1 laughing their head off - it&apos;s a worry(via @jeremyspeller) [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:22:56" id="p270" end="00:23:02">dkernohan: #jisc10 has Martin Bean been reading our LLiDA report (http://bit.ly/6jl7jy) around digital and learning literacy issues? [09:14GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:23:02" id="p271" end="00:23:05">wmjohn: Megaphones of informal learning ....... #JISC10 [09:15GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:23:05" id="p272" end="00:23:15">dajbconf: @ostephens Good point re what place would what we&apos;re experiencing now have in Martin Bean&apos;s brave new world? #jisc10 [09:15GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:23:15" id="p273" end="00:23:19">HelenBeetham: 342 000 downloads a week from Open University i-tunes-u. 88% from outside the UK. #jisc10 [09:15GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:23:19" id="p274" end="00:23:26">herrdoktorc: 88% OU iTunesU traffic is from outside the UK #jisc10 [09:15GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:23:26" id="p275" end="00:23:50">paulwalk: Bean on YouTube: &quot;Megaphones of informal learning&quot; #jisc10 [09:15GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:23:50" id="p276" end="00:23:51">manmalik: #jisc10 88% of OU itunes dnloads is from outside UK. [09:15GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:23:51" id="p277" end="00:24:07">lucyrstone: YouTube for informal learning I learnt to crochet and shared how to make meringues in return learn something give something back #jisc10 [09:15GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:24:07" id="p278" end="00:24:13">llordllama: Most iTunes University access to OU content is from outside the UK #jisc10 [09:16GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:24:13" id="p279" end="00:24:13">dianebrewster: #jisc10 M Bean showing some of the ou online resources -16million iTunesU downloads - which also result in significant website hits [09:16GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:24:13" id="p280" end="00:24:16">dajbconf: #jisc10 88% of iTunesU consumers for OU content access from outside UK. Effectively free marketing for universities. [09:16GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:24:16" id="p281" end="00:24:16">HelenBeetham: @dkernohan #jisc10 I think the LLiDA report found the idea of digital natives more problematic than Martin Bean does [09:16GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:24:16" id="p282" end="00:24:34">damyantipatel: Lots more informal learning ie via web, podcasts, YouTube etc - what impact does that have on formal learning? #jisc10 [09:16GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:24:34" id="p283" end="00:24:47">diarmaid: 88% of itunes university visitors outside the UK.  Live presentation from Martin Bean of the Open Univeristy: http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [09:16GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:24:47" id="p284" end="00:24:51">suukii: @briankelly Matron Bean - nice moniker ;-)  #JISC10 [09:16GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:24:51" id="p285" end="00:25:07">fooflington: &quot;we have people in a volcano at the moment... my insurance isn&apos;t very happy!&quot; #jisc10 [09:16GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:07" id="p286" end="00:25:16">johnpopham: Open University developing iPhone Virtual Microscope App #jisc10 [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:16" id="p287" end="00:25:18">dkernohan: 0 downloads a week from people who don&apos;t have/can&apos;t run iTunes - what was that about the digital divide? #jisc10 [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:18" id="p288" end="00:25:20">DrNickPearce: urggggh first mention of iPad #jisc10 [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:20" id="p289" end="00:25:23">iamhelenharrop: wifi is finally behaving - having my imagination captivated by Martin Bean .. great keynote #jisc10 [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:23" id="p290" end="00:25:24">llordllama: @chriskeene Now it&apos;s megaphones of informal learning.  Can we still blow our own trumpets? #jisc10 [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:24" id="p291" end="00:25:37">karenblakeman: OU now reached 16 millions download on iTunes U #jisc10 [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:37" id="p292" end="00:25:43">kirkstuff: Drinking beer really helps the flow of the JISC conf. #JISC10 (It is 9pm here btw) [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:43" id="p293" end="00:25:49">damyantipatel: Ooo cool looking microscope app #jisc10 will it beat Doodlejump though [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:49" id="p294" end="00:25:59">diarmaid: Watch the JISC 2010 conference live now: http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:25:59" id="p295" end="00:26:07">HelenBeetham: Speculating that &apos;megaphones&apos; is not really an ideal metaphor...? Do we learn best from whoever shouts loudest? #jisc10 [09:17GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:26:07" id="p296" end="00:26:10">fooflington: Also, careful not to do for iPhone what was done with Windows in the past and concentrate on a single platform #jisc10 Users demand choice. [09:18GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:26:10" id="p297" end="00:26:23">briankelly: Scary - people are watching me on the #jisc10 video stream [09:18GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:26:23" id="p298" end="00:26:26">lisaharris: 16 million downloads of OU content through iTunes Uni says VC Martin Beam at #JISC10 [09:18GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:26:26" id="p299" end="00:26:33">suukii: Would like a bit of insight into relationship between learning glitter and student learning. But will go with Bean&apos;s OER PLUG   #JISC10 [09:18GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:26:33" id="p300" end="00:26:35">jamesclay: @helenbeetham we should listen to learners, H Ford quote “If I had asked people what they wanted, they would have said faster horses #jisc10 [09:18GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:26:35" id="p301" end="00:26:40">romieh: OER key aspect of future HE M Bean #jisc10 [09:18GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:26:40" id="p302" end="00:27:12">FleurP: Great demo of megaphones of informal learning podcasts etc #jisc10 [09:18GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:27:12" id="p303" end="00:27:13">SwitchNewMedia: Streaming the #JISC10 conference today with a British Sign Language interpreter live on screen - http://bit.ly/8xzWnQ #JISC10 [09:19GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:27:13" id="p304" end="00:27:15">cyberdoyle: .@manmalik #deact and lack of decent internet connections will kill promise of technology in #digitalbritain education #jisc10 [09:19GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:27:15" id="p305" end="00:27:26">fooflington: cohere being #jisc10 &apos;ed? :) [09:19GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:27:26" id="p306" end="00:27:47">goinedge: #JISC10 Martin Bean OU: HE must be multi-channel multi-device multi-open-tools [09:19GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:27:47" id="p307" end="00:28:05">Onkloud9: Only 28% of US students feel their education is relevant, ........... Martin Bean #JISC10   Hmmmm (via @wmjohn) [09:19GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:28:05" id="p308" end="00:28:11">shirleyearley: #Jisc10 tighter funding and new technolgy encouraging collaboration -Tim oShea [09:20GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:28:11" id="p309" end="00:28:15">sputuk: Impressed with quality of #jisc10 streaming with BSL and live Twitter stream http://www.jisc.ac.uk/jisc10 [09:20GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:28:15" id="p310" end="00:28:20">andypowe11: noting that #jisc10 is in a flat room - can the people at the back see properly? [09:20GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:28:20" id="p311" end="00:28:26">iamhelenharrop: OER and the power of openness is delivering on the promises of technology and education #jisc10 [09:20GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:28:26" id="p312" end="00:28:31">briankelly: @daveyp am using Android phone to tweet with dodgy UI and autocorrect as can&apos;t access WiFi on iPod Touch #jisc10 [09:20GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:28:31" id="p313" end="00:28:36">simonhodson99: Bean: Megaphones of open learning! #jisc10 [09:20GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:28:36" id="p314" end="00:28:55">wmjohn: The #JISC10 video stream is excellent ........ no glitches, no lag, excellent picture and sound ...... Why cant all conferences be the same? [09:20GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:28:55" id="p315" end="00:29:01">iltman: Informal learning as the entry point to formal learning #jisc10 [09:20GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:01" id="p316" end="00:29:06">ostephens: 6000 students who started on Open Learn went on to pay for OU courses #jisc10 [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:06" id="p317" end="00:29:15">HelenBeetham: Impressive stat from OU: 6000 new students enrolled as a result of OpenLearn. OER business case proved I think. #jisc10 [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:15" id="p318" end="00:29:22">jobadge: boy, think my entire twitter stream is at #jisc10 [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:22" id="p319" end="00:29:25">marksmithers: And of course there is #JISC10 - another column and TweetDeck is now chirping like a demented budgie [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:25" id="p320" end="00:29:25">timmarshall: the link between informal and formal learning is important  #jisc10 [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:25" id="p321" end="00:29:33">llordllama: Just spotted a man with a giant 1 wooden paddle - will there be a train along shortly? #jisc10 [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:33" id="p322" end="00:29:37">daveyp: @briankelly That&apos;s not as good as my &quot;Sorry -- I was distracted by a UFO&quot; excuse ;-) #jisc10 [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:37" id="p323" end="00:29:56">janetfinlay: OU have 6k students join paid courses through OpenLearn - Martin Bean #jisc10 [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:29:56" id="p324" end="00:30:01">karenblakeman: @whitespider1066 iTunes U  interests so many people on my soc media workshops. Martin Bean&apos;s pres. at #jisc10 was excellent . [09:21GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:30:01" id="p325" end="00:30:08">brunella: At #JISC10 professor of informatics behind me is sleeping actually :) [09:22GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:30:08" id="p326" end="00:30:10">manmalik: #jisc10 Inst. accreditation needs to be revisited , informal learning accreditation to make way into some formal model- Martin Bean [09:22GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:30:10" id="p327" end="00:30:13">llordllama: The suit quotient at #jisc10 is high http://twitpic.com/1fa04y [09:22GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:30:13" id="p328" end="00:30:17">shirleyearley: Martin Bean #jisc10 great presentaion informal vs formal learning, and the future [09:22GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:30:17" id="p329" end="00:30:22">hectorpeebles: @sputuk @Diarmaid &amp; @SwitchNewMedia are the people responsible for the ace streaming!!! #jisc10 [09:22GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:30:22" id="p330" end="00:30:23">dajbconf: @jobadge Why aren&apos;t you at #jisc10? :-) [09:22GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:30:23" id="p331" end="00:30:43">HelenBeetham: Martin Bean mentioning role of mentors in supporting access to learning - content is not enough #jisc10 [09:22GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:30:43" id="p332" end="00:31:04">MarkPower: Hurrah for tapping into informal learning. @josiefraser...you would like this talk I think #jisc10 [09:22GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:04" id="p333" end="00:31:14">manmalik: #jisc10 I guess PLE/PLN will become more n more important for future of HE [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:14" id="p334" end="00:31:15">Onkloud9: screen grab of that slide #jisc10  http://twitpic.com/1f9yeg (via @chriskeene) [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:15" id="p335" end="00:31:16">herrdoktorc: Clouds! #jisc10 [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:16" id="p336" end="00:31:22">FleurP: Think about a way to move from informal learning to accreditation using small milestones #jisc10 #jiscenable [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:22" id="p337" end="00:31:22">HelenBeetham: @cosmo07 yes th is slippage here between &apos;UK plc&apos; and the ideal of globally shared content being &apos;for the good of all&apos;. #jisc10 [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:22" id="p338" end="00:31:30">fooflington: Having moved from WebCT to Moodle will hopefully help with the &quot;Education meets social networking&quot; model. #jisc10 [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:30" id="p339" end="00:31:33">lucyrstone: Informal learning usually means no assessment but motivated learners - let&apos;s get rid of need for continuous assessments? #jisc10 [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:33" id="p340" end="00:31:38">dajbconf: #jisc10 Smaller milestones leading to eventual institutional effectiveness is the future for HE. [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:38" id="p341" end="00:31:55">paulbrichardson: ..but keeping it informal can also be good. #jisc10. (Doesn&apos;t suit the funding model though)..... [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:31:55" id="p342" end="00:32:04">llordllama: Life Long Learners need the ability to move in and out of HE formally and informally #jisc10 [09:23GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:04" id="p343" end="00:32:10">suukii: But VC Bean - Imagine the QA hell of demonstrating the quality of accrediting mentors.   #JISC10 I value and respect informal learning but.. [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:10" id="p344" end="00:32:12">sputuk: Martin Bean showing &apos;smaller milestone&apos; model 4 learning=&gt;acreditation v current larger step model 2 compete with private sector #jisc10 [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:12" id="p345" end="00:32:21">andypowe11: &quot;imagine 100s of millions of people getting inspired to get involved in HE&quot; - informal learners - smaller accreditation steps - #jisc10 [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:21" id="p346" end="00:32:23">fooflington: @tomgillett The browser is cross platform... except when it isn&apos;t :-) #jisc10 [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:23" id="p347" end="00:32:26">jobadge: @NeilAdam I&apos;m at work in Leicester, just swamped by all my tweeps at #jisc10! [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:26" id="p348" end="00:32:28">ostephens: If OERs support informal learning, what do &apos;informal library resources&apos; look like? #jisc10 [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:28" id="p349" end="00:32:30">MarkPower: @manmalik Has to doesn&apos;t it as it underpins informal learning (using the technology) #jisc10 [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:30" id="p350" end="00:32:32">penval: #jisc10 Martin Bean and an open social cloud environment for learning &lt;= excellent ideas people and processes rule [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:32" id="p351" end="00:32:44">carenmilloy: #JISC10 informal learning is the way we can deal with globalisation and privatisation says M Bean [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:44" id="p352" end="00:32:45">Marjakingma: Life long learners need open social cloud environment, but it&apos;s still all about people and processes, not so much technology. #JISC10 [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:45" id="p353" end="00:32:50">goinedge: #JISC10 Martin Bean OU: concept of &quot;informal learners&quot; in an open social cloud environment then accreditated by HE institutions. [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:50" id="p354" end="00:32:52">manmalik: #jisc10 tech. fails mostly, hardware .  software all good but dont forget brainware - martin bean [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:52" id="p355" end="00:32:55">beckacurrant: stop playing with the exciting toys ie technology &amp; think about people and processes first. Hear bloody hear!!! #jisc10 [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:55" id="p356" end="00:32:58">dajbconf: #jisc10 People, Process, Technology
= 3 key considerations (in order of priority) &apos;Brainware&apos; not hardware. [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:32:58" id="p357" end="00:33:00">llordllama: Don&apos;t forget the brainware #jisc10 #outofgreymattererror [09:24GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:00" id="p358" end="00:33:07">elaines: Agree with Martin that learning (e- or otherwise) it&apos;s about people and process #jisc10 [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:07" id="p359" end="00:33:08">mrnick: If OERs support informal learning, what do &apos;informal library resources&apos; look like? #jisc10 (via @ostephens) [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:08" id="p360" end="00:33:09">cosmo07: M Bean &quot;don&apos;t forget about the brainware to go with technology&quot; #jisc10 [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:09" id="p361" end="00:33:12">iltman: &quot;Create the people to make sure it&apos;s successful&quot; #jisc10 [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:12" id="p362" end="00:33:14">andypowe11: &quot;most technology in education fails cos we focus on hardware and software and forget about brainware&quot; - martin bean speaking at #jisc10 [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:14" id="p363" end="00:33:26">cyberdoyle: #jisc10 &apos;lifelong learning is abt the ppl &amp; processes&apos; Martin Bean. But most learning is digital &amp; online. we need the pipes 2 deliver IT. [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:26" id="p364" end="00:33:28">simon_mcleish: Arrived at #jisc10 and sitting in corner of exhibition space - nice view across to Westminster Abbey from here on the 3rd floor [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:28" id="p365" end="00:33:32">sheilmcn: Need brainware to use software effectively #jisc10 [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:32" id="p366" end="00:33:33">marianneshepp: Process more important than technology in managing change  #jisc10 [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:33" id="p367" end="00:33:47">manmalik: #jisc10 are you proposing a cloud of HEIs Martin? [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:47" id="p368" end="00:33:55">llordllama: Call for institutions to work together there at the end - entertaining keynote #jisc10 [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:33:55" id="p369" end="00:34:05">marksmithers: Wondering if any educational technologists are working in the UK today or are they all off at  #JISC10 and #mootuk10 [09:25GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:05" id="p370" end="00:34:08">carlvincent: education technology fails because we focus on hardware and software not brain-ware #JISC10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:08" id="p371" end="00:34:18">FleurP: Change needs to start with people and processes not technology, too true. #jisc10 #jiscenable [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:18" id="p372" end="00:34:20">romieh: People and processes are what matter M Bean #jisc10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:20" id="p373" end="00:34:21">mrnick: Wish I had as much energy as Martin  Bean in the morning #jisc10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:21" id="p374" end="00:34:31">BeccaDavies: Martin Bean: When IT in education goes bad - we get enamoured with the hardware &amp;software &amp; forget about the people &amp; processes #jisc10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:31" id="p375" end="00:34:37">wmjohn: &quot;Most technology in education fails ........&quot; Martin Bean #JISC10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:37" id="p376" end="00:34:38">dajbconf: #jisc10 Question time. First question by Australian - &quot;You&apos;re not going far enough!&quot; :-D [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:38" id="p377" end="00:34:42">iamhelenharrop: sounds like Martin Bean is a #servicedesign advocate: people first, then process, then technology #jisc10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:42" id="p378" end="00:34:47">condavis10: Call me a groupie. I&apos;m fallin in love wit all my haters #jisc10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:47" id="p379" end="00:34:52">lucyrstone: Nooooooooooooo embrace the power of informal learning #jisc10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:52" id="p380" end="00:34:58">Onkloud9: Bean&apos;s talk will have been familiar to those at ALT-C last year. #jisc10 [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:34:58" id="p381" end="00:35:00">carenmilloy: Excellent keynote by Martin Bean at #JISC10 reccomend watching it [09:26GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:00" id="p382" end="00:35:02">paulwalk: That was the most engaging keynote I can remember at a JISC conf for some time - Martin Bean, #jisc10 [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:02" id="p383" end="00:35:06">learnteachshare: For those interested in #jisc10 - conference on #lifewidelearning today in 1h streamed from http://bit.ly/dhcGKc [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:06" id="p384" end="00:35:13">lisaharris: Great points from M Bean @ #JISC10, but he is preaching to the converted. How to get the message &apos;out there&apos; to decision makers? [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:13" id="p385" end="00:35:19">NicolaScull: Martin Bean at #jisc10 was challenging and inspirational. Lots for the HE sector to do to meet the changing requirements of students. [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:19" id="p386" end="00:35:34">mungeo: Martin Bean, #jisc10, successful change only possible when people, process *and* technology included, all 3 required. [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:34" id="p387" end="00:35:39">Beccie77: Very stirring keynote from Bean - Motivating as well as challenging and controversial.  This is what conferences should be like. #jisc10 [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:39" id="p388" end="00:35:56">cyberdoyle: #JISC10 content needs to be democratised. #deact is trying to break democracy. [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:56" id="p389" end="00:35:57">beckacurrant: interesting keynote that flags up many themes hrd b4 My q now is wht we do abt it? Am getting fed up w/constant debate abt the same! #jisc10 [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:35:57" id="p390" end="00:36:19">owenpeteroberts: Great keynote, great day :) #jisc10  http://tweetphoto.com/18266834 [09:27GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:36:19" id="p391" end="00:36:39">FleurP: Feeling very patriotic at the moment, aussie, aussie, aussie! ;) #jisc10 [09:28GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:36:39" id="p392" end="00:36:48">dajbconf: #jisc10 After my (almost) #question #fail at #BectaX think I&apos;ll avoid asking about how to strengthen links between schools/FE/HE... [09:28GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:36:48" id="p393" end="00:36:55">llordllama: Q: Will the #debill #deact get in the way? #jisc10 [09:28GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:36:55" id="p394" end="00:36:57">emmadw: @FleurP though sometimes a new technology can trigger an idea you&apos;d never had before.  #jisc10 #jiscenable [09:28GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:36:57" id="p395" end="00:36:57">timmarshall: where does the &quot;student experience&quot; figure in all this?  #jisc10 [09:28GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:36:57" id="p396" end="00:37:00">elaines: can&apos;t hear Martin Bazley&apos;s (?) question #jisc10 [09:28GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:00" id="p397" end="00:37:00">MarkPower: No sound coming from Tom Franklin there. I won&apos;t make the obvious comment.. ;) #jisc10 [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:00" id="p398" end="00:37:12">andypowe11: &quot;we can&apos;t always have it our way&quot; - content is being democratised - students will demand accreditation where and how they want it #jisc10 [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:12" id="p399" end="00:37:22">HelenBeetham: Content is democratised but access to higher learning and skills are not - if anything the access divide is deepening in the UK. #JISC10 [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:22" id="p400" end="00:37:25">wthashtag: #jisc10 is now trending. Do you know why? http://wthashtag.com/jisc10 define it http://cli.gs/N5S01 [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:25" id="p401" end="00:37:33">lisparcell: #jisc10 HE needs to move towards enabling students to make sense of information, access and retrieval not enough [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:33" id="p402" end="00:37:36">manmalik: #jisc10 napster - reason behind ipod&apos;s design [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:36" id="p403" end="00:37:40">kirkstuff: #jisc10 has made the top ten of trending topics, just as I spotyed the first spam hijacking it! [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:40" id="p404" end="00:37:44">dajbconf: #jisc10 Wondering why we have to stand up to ask questions- why not put Twitter stream on screen? [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:44" id="p405" end="00:37:49">spiky7: Enjoying #jisc10 tweets, still impressed how popular Martin Bean is; will it last? [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:37:49" id="p406" end="00:38:06">cyberdoyle: Martin Bean &apos; napster challenged the business models of the music industry via the Ipod&apos;  #JISC10 #deact [09:29GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:38:06" id="p407" end="00:38:16">hwilliamson: great keynote by Martin Bean - great start to the day #jisc10 [09:30GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:38:16" id="p408" end="00:38:25">andypowe11: &quot;ipod would never have happened without napster&quot;... similarly, oer will challenge many of our long-standing assumptions #jisc10 [09:30GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:38:25" id="p409" end="00:38:38">suukii: Tom Franklin raises issues we&apos;ve saddled ourselves with thanks to stupid digital economy bill  #JISC10 #debill. Bean says morph and evolve! [09:30GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:38:38" id="p410" end="00:39:17">dianebrewster: &quot;most technology in education fails cos we focus on hardware and software and forget about brainware&quot; -martin bean #jisc10 (via @andypowe11) [09:30GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:39:17" id="p411" end="00:39:27">HelenBeetham: I think HE should be democratising access to professions, social power, research communities: free content is not democracy #JISC10 [09:31GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:39:27" id="p412" end="00:39:51">mkdDCC: at #jisc10, feeling thoroughly twitter-deluged. [09:31GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:39:51" id="p413" end="00:39:52">beckacurrant: so how do we rebuild and redesign HE? How do we make real, substantitive changes to student experience &amp; bring ppl with us? #jisc10 [09:31GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:39:52" id="p414" end="00:39:59">lucyrstone: @dajbconf has FE been mentioned at all yet? I won&apos;t do my usual rant about my loan voice for FE #jisc10 [09:31GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:39:59" id="p415" end="00:40:02">dajbconf: #jisc10 OER will disrupt HE in same way Napster disrupted music industry (and led to iPod according to Mr Bean) [09:31GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:40:02" id="p416" end="00:40:09">BeccaDavies: So are public libraries the &quot;oldest&quot; form of OER &amp; how/where when should we be working with them to support the OER developed in HE? #jisc10 [09:32GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:40:09" id="p417" end="00:40:17">dkernohan: &quot;iPod wouldn&apos;t have happened without Napster challenging old business models&quot;. iPod *is* the old business models! #jisc10 [09:32GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:40:17" id="p418" end="00:40:39">suukii: But as I see it #debill was about massive retrenchment  #JISC10. So uk gov sleep walks into curtailing the digital economy thanks 2 lobbies [09:32GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:40:39" id="p419" end="00:40:40">ostephens: @andypowe11 will there be a napster for (O)ERs? #jisc10 [09:32GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:40:40" id="p420" end="00:40:57">scottcolfer: #jisc10 great keynote via live feed. Bricks &amp; mortar Vs Clicks &amp; mortar - interested to see if this could be extended to maintained schools [09:32GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:40:57" id="p421" end="00:41:11">whaa: Resorting to 3G dongle for access at #jisc10 Delegates overloading the provided wifi again! [09:32GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:11" id="p422" end="00:41:12">lucyrstone: @dajbconf you can almost feel the fear reminds me of being at school #jisc10 [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:12" id="p423" end="00:41:25">benelwell: Does Martin Bean at #jisc10 look anything like Rowan Atkinson? #MrBean [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:25" id="p424" end="00:41:36">paulbrichardson: Agreeing the &apos;Supported Open Learning&apos; is a useful term. Can be supported by a range of technologies.. #jisc10 [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:36" id="p425" end="00:41:36">pressfuturist: @andypowe11 Thanks for tweeting the Martin Bean speech at #jisc10 - looking forward to his lecture at the C4 event this evening! [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:36" id="p426" end="00:41:40">llordllama: ....and we&apos;re running over already...  #jisc10 [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:40" id="p427" end="00:41:40">dianebrewster: That was the most engaging keynote I can remember at a JISC conf for some time - Martin Bean, #jisc10 (via @paulwalk) [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:40" id="p428" end="00:41:43">dajbconf: @lucyrstone Not really... Martin Bean VC of OU so kind of understandable given his context. #jisc10 [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:43" id="p429" end="00:41:58">kirkstuff: not so different following online as being at #jisc10 ,can still drift of at the questions as usual *Much* more value with the twitterstream [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:58" id="p430" end="00:41:58">manmalik: #jisc10 university libraries need to do more on developing skills with students for wikipedia and google age [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:41:58" id="p431" end="00:42:04">MarkPower: @hwilliamson Yep, excellent. Good to see noise around informal learning &amp; learner control is going to build (it will have to imo) #jisc10 [09:33GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:42:04" id="p432" end="00:42:26">HelenBeetham: OER is not to HE as napster is to the music industry - universities have always been (more or less) public bodies in the UK #jisc10 [09:34GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:42:26" id="p433" end="00:42:28">manmalik: #jisc10 @briankelly  ON [09:34GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:42:28" id="p434" end="00:42:36">Marjakingma: Bean repeats need for libraries to teach users what information resources to trust and not just to rely on Google and Wikipedia. #JISC10 [09:34GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:42:36" id="p435" end="00:42:43">lucyrstone: Make my children look at books as well as Google for every bit of homework to find reliable sources not sure all teachers do same #jisc10 [09:34GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:42:43" id="p436" end="00:42:47">manmalik: #jisc10 @briankelly  u ask my CLE question :) [09:34GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:42:47" id="p437" end="00:42:50">dajbconf: #jisc10 You can only ask questions if you&apos;re male, white and middle-aged ;-) [09:34GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:42:50" id="p438" end="00:43:00">electricchalk: Martin echoing a point made by @hblanchett yesterday about crucial role of libraries in information literacy #jisc10 [09:34GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:00" id="p439" end="00:43:01">TerryWassall: #jisc10 &quot;171 more tweets since you started searching&quot;. I give in. [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:01" id="p440" end="00:43:07">fooflington: Loving the #bsl sign for #twitter at #jisc10 :) [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:07" id="p441" end="00:43:29">Onkloud9: #JISC10 Bean OU: concept of &quot;informal learners&quot; in an open social cloud environment then accreditated by HE institutions. (via @goinedge) [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:29" id="p442" end="00:43:38">llordllama: Time to augment my name badge with my twitter ID #jisc10 [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:38" id="p443" end="00:43:43">timmarshall: openess and ROI are not mutually exclusive  #jisc10 [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:43" id="p444" end="00:43:46">beckacurrant: signing off now to present session will be back on twitter later! Haven&apos;t yet figured out how to tweet &amp; present at same time... #jisc10 [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:46" id="p445" end="00:43:47">ruthycl: Nice to see a VC really supporting libraries and their contemporary role in ed and info lit.  #jisc10 [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:47" id="p446" end="00:43:48">manmalik: #jisc10 JISC really important to us - M Bean. SaS is great example, more n more Cloud based computing YAY [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:43:48" id="p447" end="00:44:08">lucyrstone: #jisc10 great keynote lots to think about think the guy signing was amazing too [09:35GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:44:08" id="p448" end="00:44:11">HelenBeetham: Digital literacies essential but th are risks in locating them only in the library: &apos;making meaning&apos; happens in subjects/curricula #jisc10 [09:36GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:44:11" id="p449" end="00:44:15">lisparcell: #jisc10 good question from Brian Kelly about HE relying on today&apos;s cool technology- is google and twitter tomorrow&apos;s blackboard - small b:-) [09:36GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:44:15" id="p450" end="00:44:24">goinedge: #JISC10 Martin Bean OU - question time - idea of &quot;spectrum&quot; of services,  provenience of information, role of libraries. [09:36GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:44:24" id="p451" end="00:44:25">manmalik: #jisc10 IT cottage industry is dead, we do not need to do the code and infrastucture over and over again [09:36GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:44:25" id="p452" end="00:44:57">ostephens: The UK is too smaller place for each University to have its own datacentre - Martin Bean at #jisc10 [09:36GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:44:57" id="p453" end="00:44:58">MarkPower: Clap for Martin Bean at #jisc10. Sorry, I&apos;ll rephrase.....*applause* ;) [09:36GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:44:58" id="p454" end="00:45:02">dajbconf: @dkernohan I agree, Spotify FTW! #jisc10 [09:36GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:45:02" id="p455" end="00:45:11">alphabeta85: Great opening keynote from Martin Bean #jisc10 [09:37GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:45:11" id="p456" end="00:45:13">sheilmcn: Some critical choices need to be made around the cloud and sas architectures #jisc10 [09:37GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:45:13" id="p457" end="00:45:16">iltman: Good stuff from Martin Bean #jisc10 [09:37GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:45:16" id="p458" end="00:45:28">andypowe11: we have no choice but to embrace the cloud - &quot;the uk is too small for each of us to have our own data centre&quot; - martin bean at #jisc10 [09:37GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:45:28" id="p459" end="00:45:47">elaines: Martin Bean- using cloud services/shared services doesn&apos;t mean an institution will loose its uniqueness. #jisc10 [09:37GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:45:47" id="p460" end="00:45:50">richardmobbs: Ahhh!!! #jisc10 server crash :( [09:37GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:45:50" id="p461" end="00:45:53">sputuk: UK is too small for each HEI to have its own data center (re: cloud and it&apos;s role from Martin Bean #jisc10) [09:37GMT]</p> 
<p style="s1" begin="00:45:53" id="p462" end="00:46:09">benelwell: @damyantipatel That&apos;s a shame. I&apos;m sure Mr Bean would have made #jisc10 more amusing [09:37GMT]</p> 
		</div> 
	</body> 
</tt>
